http://www.lbps.net/j3site/index.php/privacy-policy

HomeNewsResourcesShopAbout the LBPSsearchLog In/Out
You are here:
Privacy Policy
LBPS.net is aware that you care how information about you is used and shared and we appreciate your trust in us to do that carefully and sensibly. This notice describes the privacy policy of LBPS.net.
By visiting LBPS.net, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Notice.
Controllers of Personal Information
EU General Data Protection Regulations
What Personal Information About Customers Does LBPS.net Gather?
What About Cookies?
Does LBPS.net Share the Information it Receives?
What Information Can I Access?
What Choices Do I Have?
Examples of Information Collected
Controllers of Personal Information
Any personal information provided to or gathered by LBPS.net is controlled by The Lowland and Border Pipers’ Society (the data controller), Stables Cottage, Winton Gardens, Pencaitland, Scotland
Back to top
EU General Data Protection Regulations
From the 25th May, 2018 data held, and its processing on the site will conform to the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR ) under the 'Legitimate Interests' lawful basis. Our legitimate interest is in receiving subscriptions from members and in providing the services that subscribers are entitled to. These services cover
providing online access to the Society Journal (and delivery of printed copy where provided for in the subscription)
discount prices in the online shop.
Delivery of goods purchased in the shop
Newsletters provided by email; users can unsubscribe to this service
The only data we hold and process is that necessary to realise this interest. We do not pass the data we hold to any other processor except where to do so is required by law. All the mandatory information we hold is necessary to provide the services we offer; users are able to withhold other personal information if they deem it in their interest to do so.
The information we hold is available for viewing or update via the user profile
Users can request that their data be removed from our records by emailing the data controller (This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.) Doing so will cancel the subscription and remove access to all services provided by that subscription.
Back to top
What Personal Information About Customers Does LBPS.net Gather?
The information we learn from customers helps us personalise and continually improve your experience at LBPS.net. We use the information to handle orders, deliver products and services, process payments, communicate with you about orders, products, services and promotional offers, update our records and generally maintain your accounts with us. We also use this information to prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our site.
Here are the types of information we gather.
Information You Give Us: we receive and store any information you enter on our website or give us in any other way. Click here to see examples of what we collect. You can choose not to provide certain information but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of our features. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests and communicating with you.
Automatic Information: we receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many websites, we do not currently use "cookies" on this site; should we decide to do so in the future, for instance to obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses LBPS, details of examples of the information we can receive can be viewed by clicking here.
E-mail Communications: to help us make e-mails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open e-mail from LBPS.net if your computer supports such capabilities.
Back to top
What About Cookies?
We do not currently use cookies on this site; However, we may decide to do so in the future, and information on how this might work is included here.
Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser and to provide features such as the storage of items in your Shopping Basket between visits.
The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on's settings or visiting the website of its manufacturer. However, because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of LBPS.net's essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. For instance, if you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you will not be able to add items to your Shopping Cart, proceed to Checkout, or use any LBPS.net products and services that require you to Sign in.
If you do leave cookies turned on, be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer.
Back to top
Does LBPS.net share the Information it receives?
Information about our customers is an important part of our business and we are not in the business of selling it to others. LBPS.net does not share any of the customer information it collects with the exception of
Third Party Service Providers: We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal materials, processing credit card payments and providing customer service. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. Further, they must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Notice and as permitted by the UK's Data Protection Act and, after the 25th May, 2018,  the EU General Data Protection Regulations.
Protection of LBPS.net and Others: We will release account and other personal information if we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; enforce or apply our Conditions of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property or safety of LBPS.net, our users or others.
Back to top
What Information Can I Access?
LBPS.net gives you access to a broad range of information about your account and your interactions with LBPS.net for the limited purpose of viewing and, in certain cases, updating that information. All available information can be viewed and edited by visiting 'Your Profile', available from the Log-in form.
Back to top
What Choices Do I Have?
As discussed above, you can always choose not to provide information, even though it might be needed to make a purchase or to take advantage of LBPS.net features such as your profile and account history. Certain areas of the site will only be available to you once you have provided the information requested.
You can add or update certain information on pages such as those referenced above.
Back to top
Examples of Information Collected
Information You Give Us
You provide most such information when you buy, participate in a forum or questionnaire or communicate with customer services. For example, you provide information when you place an order through LBPS. provide information in your account (and you might have more than one if you have used more than one e-mail address when shopping with us) or your profile; communicate with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise; provide and post reviews; and employ other personal notification services such as such as Available to Order Notifications. As a result of those actions, you might supply us with such information as: your name; address and phone number; people to whom purchases have been shipped (including addresses and phone numbers), content of reviews and e-mails to us; the personal description in your profile... We do not collect credit card information.
Automatic Information
Examples of the information we collect and analyse include: the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, login; e-mail address, password, computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system and platform [necessary for correct display of our pages in your browser]; purchase history, the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our website (including date and time). During some visits we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, and methods used to browse away from the page. These functions are performed automatically by our web hosts and used to analyse site usage and improve our services; information used to analyse site usage, as listed above, is not linked to your personal data.
Back to top
Remember Me
Log in
Forgot Login?
Sign up
Contact WebmasterContact the LBPSSite mapA guide to using this site
Forgot Login?
Sign up
